<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Azure - Category - NASAN</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/categories/azure/</link><description>Azure - Category - NASAN</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 06:10:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nasan92.github.io/categories/azure/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Securing Resources in Azure VMs with Microsoft Entra Private Access in a Hub-and-Spoke Architecture</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-08-31-entraprivateaccess/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 06:10:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-08-31-entraprivateaccess/</guid><description>I did a little Microsoft Entra Private Access Test setup.
My goal was to test access to some private Resources hosted on Azure Virtual Machines with Microsoft Entra Private Access instead of VPN.
Overview The test setup is illustrated below: Preview I have one Virtual Machine (VM) with a Windows File Share that I wish to access from my endpoint and I also want to be able to access this VM via RDP.</description></item><item><title>AzureAD App Registrations explained</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-05-01-azureappregistrations-explained/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 05:51:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-05-01-azureappregistrations-explained/</guid><description>Azure AD App registration Recently I had some talks with developers which made me to realize that I didn&amp;rsquo;t fully understand how App Registrations are working. I was aware that we are registering an app and allowing the app certain permissions but in detail I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand it.
Why Azure AD App registration? Basically for every app where you want to use the Microsoft Identity Platform, you need to register your app.</description></item><item><title>SC-100 - Microsoft Certified Cybersecurity Architect Expert - MindMap Collection</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-01-13-microsoftcybersecurityarchitect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 10:51:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-01-13-microsoftcybersecurityarchitect/</guid><description>Studying SC-100 In my recent self-study, I have been working through the Microsoft SC-100 learning path. One of the ways that I have been organizing and consolidating my learning is by creating mind maps of the key concepts and topics covered in the course.
You can find some of those mind maps below:
Design a Zero Trust strategy and architecture Build an overall security strategy and architecture: Preview Design a security operations strategy: Preview Design an identity security strategy: Preview Evaluate Governance Risk Compliance (GRC) technical strategies and security operations strategies Evaluate a regulatory compliance strategy Preview Evaluate Security Posture - Manage Risk Preview Design security for infrastructure Preview Design strategy for data and applications Preview Recommend security best practices Security best practices using Microsoft Cybersecurity Reference Architectures (MCRA) and Microsoft Cloud Security Benchmarks Preview</description></item><item><title>Stop Azure Backup for multiple SQL on Azure VM Databases with Powershell</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-10-28-stopbackupformultipleazuresqlonvmdatabases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 10:51:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-10-28-stopbackupformultipleazuresqlonvmdatabases/</guid><description>link: https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/backup/backup-azure-sql-automation#stop-protection
I had a case where I did need to migrate a lot of databases from one SQL Server on a Azure VM to another VM. After the successful migration there were a lot of old databases on the &amp;ldquo;old SQL Server&amp;rdquo; offline and I got a lot of Azure Backup Alerts. Because I was to lazy to disable the backup for each database by hand, I created the following small script which will do that job.</description></item><item><title>Azure - Create a Custom RBAC Role to allow Stop - Start of all Azure Virtual Machines in a Subscription with Terraform</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-09-08-createcustomroleterraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 10:51:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-09-08-createcustomroleterraform/</guid><description>Yes&amp;hellip; its annoying there is no built in role to only allow restarting of Azure Virtual Machines&amp;hellip; The Virtual Machine Contributor Role allows to much. With this role you are able to destory and create VMs..
So what I want to do in this case is creating a custom role which only allows to start / stop / restart Virtual Machines. And I want to do that with terraform because I&amp;rsquo;m doing the whole Azure Resource Deployment with terraform anyway.</description></item><item><title>MLOps explained - MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-04-22-mlops-explained/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 13:39:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-04-22-mlops-explained/</guid><description>This MindMap was created using the following Microsoft Youtube Video: MLOps explained | Machine Learning Essentials
Preview</description></item><item><title>Azure Monitor MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-02-21-azuremonitor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 13:39:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-02-21-azuremonitor/</guid><description>I created this Azure Monitor MindMap last year to get a better Overview over Azure Monitor. I&amp;rsquo;ve created it based on the Azure Monitor Documentation. Somethings may be outdated today -&amp;gt; you can find the Microsoft Docs to that topic here: Azure Monitor
Preview</description></item></channel></rss>