<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Azure - Tag - NASAN</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/tags/azure/</link><description>Azure - Tag - NASAN</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 05:15:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nasan92.github.io/tags/azure/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mark's Simos List of Cybersecurity Resources - MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-05-18-markslistofcybersecurityresources/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 05:15:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-05-18-markslistofcybersecurityresources/</guid><description>Based on Mark&amp;rsquo;s List of cybersecurity Resources, I created the following Mind Map:
Preview</description></item><item><title>Stop Azure Backup for multiple SQL on Azure VM Databases with Powershell</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-10-28-stopbackupformultipleazuresqlonvmdatabases/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 10:51:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-10-28-stopbackupformultipleazuresqlonvmdatabases/</guid><description>link: https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/backup/backup-azure-sql-automation#stop-protection
I had a case where I did need to migrate a lot of databases from one SQL Server on a Azure VM to another VM. After the successful migration there were a lot of old databases on the &amp;ldquo;old SQL Server&amp;rdquo; offline and I got a lot of Azure Backup Alerts. Because I was to lazy to disable the backup for each database by hand, I created the following small script which will do that job.</description></item><item><title>Azure - Create a Custom RBAC Role to allow Stop - Start of all Azure Virtual Machines in a Subscription with Terraform</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-09-08-createcustomroleterraform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 10:51:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-09-08-createcustomroleterraform/</guid><description>Yes&amp;hellip; its annoying there is no built in role to only allow restarting of Azure Virtual Machines&amp;hellip; The Virtual Machine Contributor Role allows to much. With this role you are able to destory and create VMs..
So what I want to do in this case is creating a custom role which only allows to start / stop / restart Virtual Machines. And I want to do that with terraform because I&amp;rsquo;m doing the whole Azure Resource Deployment with terraform anyway.</description></item><item><title>MLOps explained - MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-04-22-mlops-explained/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 13:39:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-04-22-mlops-explained/</guid><description>This MindMap was created using the following Microsoft Youtube Video: MLOps explained | Machine Learning Essentials
Preview</description></item><item><title>Azure Monitor MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-02-21-azuremonitor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 13:39:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-02-21-azuremonitor/</guid><description>I created this Azure Monitor MindMap last year to get a better Overview over Azure Monitor. I&amp;rsquo;ve created it based on the Azure Monitor Documentation. Somethings may be outdated today -&amp;gt; you can find the Microsoft Docs to that topic here: Azure Monitor
Preview</description></item><item><title>MindMap Hybrid Identity with Azure AD - AD Connect</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-02-19-hybrididentity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 07:53:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2022-02-19-hybrididentity/</guid><description>You can find the official documentation from Microsoft to that topic here: Microsoft Docs - Hybrid Identity
In this MindMap you can see the different Authentication and Single Sign On Methods which are available. Preview</description></item></channel></rss>