<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>MindMap - Category - NASAN</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/categories/mindmap/</link><description>MindMap - Category - NASAN</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:10:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nasan92.github.io/categories/mindmap/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Früchte des Herzens - MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-11-11-fr%C3%BCchte-des-herzens/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:10:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-11-11-fr%C3%BCchte-des-herzens/</guid><description><![CDATA[Kürzlich hörte ich mir den Vortrag &ldquo;Übers Wasser gehen für Anfänger&rdquo; von Johannes Hartl an.
Der Vortrag behandelt das Thema: &ldquo;Wie gehst Du mit tiefer Trauer und tiefem Leid um?&rdquo;
Gegen Schluss des Vortrages zeigt er auf was für mögliche Früchte auf dem Boden von herausfordernden Situationen entstehen können.
Sogenannte Früchte des Herzens. Diese habe ich in folgendem MindMap veranschaulicht:
![MindMap](/images/Fruechte- des-Herzens.svg &ldquo;Preview&rdquo;)]]></description></item><item><title>Psychologie - MindMaps</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-10-26-psychologie-mindmap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 05:10:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-10-26-psychologie-mindmap/</guid><description>Anhand des sehr unterhaltsamen Buches Klo-Psychologe: In 100 Sitzungen zum Seelenklempner habe ich mich nach hundert lehrreichen Sitzungen entscheiden, ein paar MindMaps zur Übersicht der Themen zu erstellen.
Folgendes MindMap zur Übersicht der Hauptthemen, welche im Buch behandelt wurden:
Übersicht Preview 1. Tiefenpsychologie Preview 2. Persönlichtkeitspsychologie Preview 3. Kognitive Psychologie und Intelligenz-Psychologie Preview 4. Kommunikationspsychologie Preview 5. Motivationspsychologie und positive Psychologie Preview 6. Entwicklungs und Evolutionspsychologie Preview 7. Organisationspsychologie Preview</description></item><item><title>Steal like an Artist - MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-09-15-steallikeanartist/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 05:10:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-09-15-steallikeanartist/</guid><description>MindMap for the Book
Steal Like an Artist: 10 Things Nobody Told You About Being Creative
Preview</description></item><item><title>SC-300 - Microsoft Identity and Access Administrator - MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-09-14-sc300-mindmap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 05:10:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-09-14-sc300-mindmap/</guid><description>Note: My Microsoft Cybersecurity Architect MindMap covers already a lot of topics mentioned here: SC-100 MindMap Collection
This MindMap is based on the MS Learning path: SC-300 Preview</description></item><item><title>Certificates (SSL/HTTPS)- MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-09-09-certificates/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 05:10:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-09-09-certificates/</guid><description>Certificates MindMap:
SSL certificates - what? why? How do certificates work? Types of certificates How HTTPS encryption works CERTIFICATION AUTHORITIES (CA) .. Preview</description></item><item><title>AZ-500 - Azure Security Engineer - MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-09-08-az500-mindmap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 05:10:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-09-08-az500-mindmap/</guid><description>Note: My Microsoft Cybersecurity Architect MindMap covers already a lot of topics mentioned here: SC-100 MindMap Collection
This MindMap is based on the MS Learning path: AZ-500 Preview</description></item><item><title>Mark's Simos List of Cybersecurity Resources - MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-05-18-markslistofcybersecurityresources/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 05:15:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-05-18-markslistofcybersecurityresources/</guid><description>Based on Mark&amp;rsquo;s List of cybersecurity Resources, I created the following Mind Map:
Preview</description></item><item><title>Top 10 Active Directory Attack Methods and How To Protect against it - MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-05-18-top10adattackmethods/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 05:10:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-05-18-top10adattackmethods/</guid><description>MindMap with Top 10 Active Directory Attack methods and How to Protect against them:
Preview</description></item><item><title>Factfulness by Hans Rosling - MindMap</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-05-13-factfulness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 10:51:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-05-13-factfulness/</guid><description>MindMap for the Book
Factfulness: Ten Reasons We&amp;rsquo;re Wrong About The World - And Why Things Are Better Than You Think - by Hans Rosling
Preview</description></item><item><title>SC-100 - Microsoft Certified Cybersecurity Architect Expert - MindMap Collection</title><link>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-01-13-microsoftcybersecurityarchitect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 10:51:21 +0100</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://nasan92.github.io/posts/2023-01-13-microsoftcybersecurityarchitect/</guid><description>Studying SC-100 In my recent self-study, I have been working through the Microsoft SC-100 learning path. One of the ways that I have been organizing and consolidating my learning is by creating mind maps of the key concepts and topics covered in the course.
You can find some of those mind maps below:
Design a Zero Trust strategy and architecture Build an overall security strategy and architecture: Preview Design a security operations strategy: Preview Design an identity security strategy: Preview Evaluate Governance Risk Compliance (GRC) technical strategies and security operations strategies Evaluate a regulatory compliance strategy Preview Evaluate Security Posture - Manage Risk Preview Design security for infrastructure Preview Design strategy for data and applications Preview Recommend security best practices Security best practices using Microsoft Cybersecurity Reference Architectures (MCRA) and Microsoft Cloud Security Benchmarks Preview</description></item></channel></rss>